한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
VEEP (부통령) S02E10
D.C.
Original Air Date 2013-06-23
행정부에 대한 의심의 먹구름은
아직도 걷히지 않고 있습니다
A cloud of suspicion
hangs over this administration.
또 무슨 음모며
거짓말이 도사리고 있는 걸까요?
Were there cover-ups?
Lies?
짜증나 저 놈의 고발 프로들
무슨 90년대도 아니고
Oh, God.
I hate impeachments.
They're so '90s.
상원이고 하원이고 모두 대통령을
구워삶고 있으니
Well, the president
now has the Senate
and the House after him.
Gonna rain pain.
대통령은 그냥 끝났어요
그래서 대통령은 어쩔 생각이래?
(POTUS : President Of The U.S.)
So what's POTUS's
next move, Jonah?
아, 그건 기밀이라서요
Oh, these lips are on lockdown.
모르는 주제에 기밀은 무슨
Right.
You don't know.
그게 아니고 저는
"묻지도 말하지도 말 것"으로 응대해야 해요
No, I just have a "don't ask
don't tell" policy
제가 아는 것이든,
about the things that I know.
제가 모르는 일이든간에 말이죠
Or that I don't know.
조나, 니 아가리랑 몸뚱이 모두 보기 싫으니
Jonah, don't talk, don't stay.
얼른 궁둥짝 들고
잘난 백악관으로 꺼져버려
You need to fuck off
and go back to Westworld.
- 하지만 부통령님-
- 꺼지라고
- But, ma'am--
- You need to fuck off.
- 하지만 부통령님-
- 꺼지라 했다?
- But, ma'am--
- I said fuck off.
- 세 번이나 말했으면 좀 꺼져라
- 알겠습니다 부통령님
- Three fucks, you're out.
- Yes, ma'am.
음, 모두들 내 집무실로 좀 모이지
Yeah. Uh, guys, everybody
in my office, please.
개리, 너는 내 옆자리에 앉아주렴
Um, Gary, why don't you
come sit here next to me?
알겠습니다
Okay.
이미 에이미한테 말한 거지만
I've already told Amy this,
모두에게 꼭 해야 할
말이 있어
but I have something
that I need to tell you all.
무슨 말씀일지 다 알아요
I think I know
what you're gonna say.
2년 남은 부통령직 관두기로 했어
I've decided I'm not
going to join POTUS
in the next election.
I'm gonna get out.
안 할 거라고
그래
Yeah.
부통령님 정말 진심으로 유감입니다
Ma'am, you have my deepest,
deepest sympathies.
나 죽은 거 아니거든?
Okay, well, I'm not dead.
내 생각은,
My plan is
2년 남은 부통령 자리는 때려치우고
that I'm gonna leave
in two years,
차차기 대통령 선거에 출마하는거지
but then I'm gonna
run for president
차기 대통령 취임 4년 뒤에 말이야
four years after that.
하지만 그러는 사이에
여러분들과 함께 할 수 없으니 말이지
But in the meantime, I obviously
can't keep everybody on.
괜찮아요
No, it's okay.
혹시 다른 직업을 구해야 한다면
So if you need
to look for other jobs,
미리 생각해두라고 하는 말이야
then you need
to be thinking about that.
벌써부터 그럴 사람이 어디 있어요?
부통령님?
No one's thinking about that
right now, ma'am.
그럼요
Furthest thing from our minds.
아직 이해가 안 되는데요
I'm still digesting
the information.
실례지만 매우 급한 전화를
좀 받아야겠습니다
Although I should
really take this call.
- 괜찮겠죠?
- 그래 그래 그래
- Yeah?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
나에 대한 충성심이..
Well, your devotion
to this job...
- ..참 돋는구나 댄..
- 감사합니다 부통령님,
- Yeah. Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- ...it's just inspiring, Dan.
저 자식 전화 받으러 가는 게 아니고
전화하러 가는거지?
He's not getting a call.
He's making a call, right?
여보세요, 네,
Hi. Yes.
청 주지사님한테 말씀 좀 전해주세요
Can you please
tell Governor Chung
댄 이건이 긴밀히
대화를 요청한다고요
that Dan Egan is ready
for the Chung chat?
안녕하세요 맥켄지 의원님
Hi, Senator McKensie. How are you?
정말 부통령님이 관두리라 생각해?
You really think she'll go?
그것 참 안됐네
God, that's such a shame.
맞아, 내가 실업자가 되는 거나 마찬가지야
No, it means I have
absolutely nothing to do.
부통령님 말이야
I meant for her.
어떻게 보면 우리 둘이
같이 있을 시간이 늘어나긴 하겠네
Still, this might mean
that we could spend
more time together.
_
이제 매일매일 하는거야
Let's take it
one day at a time.
워머나 세상에
Sweet Jesus.
급작스러운 요청에
응해주셔서 감사합니다 데이비슨 씨
Thank you so much for seeing me at
such short notice, Mr. Davison.
마다할 리가요 윌슨 양
Happy to, Miss Wilson.
저는 윌슨 양의 업무 효율성과
정확성에 대해 높이 평가하고 있습니다
I'm an ardent admirer of your
efficiency and precision.
그러시다면 바로 본론으로 들어가죠
Oh, well, in that case,
let's get right to it.
좋아요, 윌슨 양의
절도 있는 일처리는 정말 좋습니다
Excellent.
I respect your brevity.
무서울 정도로 칼같죠
It's almost threatening.
네, 코진스키 의원님
Yes, Congressman Kosynski.
제게는 의원님이 아니라
멘토시지만요
Or should I say
mentor Kosynski?
그럼요, 저는 의원님을
제 멘토로 늘 동경해왔습니다
Yes, sir. Well, I always
thought of you as a mentor.
의원님은 저희 아버지보다도
더 아버지로 삼고 싶은 분입니다
The father figure my own dad was
too weird and distant to be.
자기랑 나랑 같이 자고
다음날 아침 신문 읽었던 거 기억나?
Like that night that you stayed over and
we read the papers the next morning?
- 그럼
- 정말 좋았어
- Uh-huh.
- That was really nice.
문득 생각이 들었는데
And I thought, yeah,
that is something
그런 여유로운 삶이야말로
내 남은 생애 동안 살고 싶은 삶이야
that I could do
for the rest of my life.
그래, 나도 자기랑 같이
잠자고 신문 읽는거 좋아하긴 하는데..
Yeah, well, you know,
I like sleep and newspapers
- as much as the next person, but...
- Right.
맞아
그런데 네 남은 평생동안?
the rest of your life?
그렇게 누워만 있다가
몸에 욕창 생기겠어
You know, you're gonna
get bedsores.
대화를 나눠보니 우리 드림 메트릭 팀
일원으로 섭외하고 싶어졌습니다
I would have no problem
finding you a position
within my Dream Metric team.
Sound good?
마음에 드시죠?
- 물론입니다
- 이렇게나 궁합이 잘 맞는다니
- Yes, sir.
- We are simpatico.
- 약속한겁니다
- 함께 일하게 되어 영광입니다
- We have a deal.
- Pleasure doing business with you, sir.
네, 네 블랙웰 판사님 안녕하세요
Yes, yes. Justice
Blackwell, how are you?
다시 전화주셔서 정말 감사합니다
Thank you so much
for calling me back.
- 자네 빠른가?
- 그럼요
- You fast?
- Oh, yeah.
제 별명이 워싱턴의 번개라고요
They call me
the Washington Flash.
그럴 리가
I doubt that.
아무튼 빨리 시작해보자고
All right, let's get
this over with ASAP.
이 존나 허우대만 멀쩡한
It's not gonna be easy
with this big, gangly
보지년같은 새끼가-
piss flap over here
who moves like--
니년이 어떻게 느리다고 했지?
hey, what do you
move like, Will?
저는 흑인 젊은이 사망 사건을
수사하는 미시시피 탐정만큼이나
I move as slowly
as a Mississippi detective
investigating the murder
of a young black man.
느릿느릿하죠
그렇지
준비됐나 마이크?
That's right.
Ready, Mike?
그럼요- 아 바로 따라가겠습니다
Yeah, abso-- oh.
Right behind you.
부통령님이 사직하신다고 하면
대통령님이 엄청 충격받으실 거예요
Hey, ma'am, you know
you're gonna break
the president's heart
with this news.
_
맘같아선 척추라도 꺾어버리고 싶은데
Wish I could break his spine.
그럴 수가 없어,
인간 젤리라서 척추가 없겠지
But I can't, 'cause
it's made of Jell-O.
제발요! 각하께서 부통령이 되신 건
미국 역사상 최고 경사예요
Come on, you being veep is the best
thing that's ever happened to America.
아냐, 존나 좆같았어
Gary, it has been shit.
- 아니라고요!
- 좆같았어, 난 빠져나가겠어
- No, it hasn't.
- It has. I'm getting out.
- 오, 부통령님
- 내가 좀전에 뭐라고 했지?
- Oh, Madam Vice President.
- What did I tell you earlier?
- 또요?
- 그래
- Again?
- Yeah.
좀 비키지 벤?
대통령 각하를 만나야 해서
Excuse me, Ben.
Gonna go see the president.
안됩니다, 각하,
취소되셔서요
Uh, no. No, you're not.
He's canceled.
대신 저와 얘기하시죠
And you're gonna
meet with me instead.
부통령님, 오전에 드리려던 말씀은
Ma'am, that is what I was going
to tell you earlier today
- 그러니까 각하께서 저한테-
- 꺼지라 했다!
- until you told me to--
- Fuck off.
제 문장을 완성해주시는건가요?
아니면 똑같은 말씀을 하시는건가요?
Are you finishing my sentence or
are you telling me that again?
둘 다다
Both.
알겠습니다
Yes, ma'am.
좋아요, 이 쪽으로 오시죠
Good.
Go ahead.
의원님!
Congressman...
엄청 빠르시네요
Wow, you're fast.
혹시 일류 언론담당 보좌관을
새로 뽑을 생각이 있으신가 해서요
Just wondering if you
could use a top press guy.
니 몸뚱이 따위는 필요 없어 마이크
Ha! I really don't have
any need for you, Mike.
넌 무능력의 결정체잖아
You're kind of obsolete.
1200년 전 바이킹 족보다도
쓰잘데없는 놈
You're like a Viking
stuck in time.
- 전 인맥이 엄청나요
- 그러셔?
- I have excellent contacts.
- Really?
몹시 고위직의 분들 말이죠
Very high up people, sir.
Very high up.
그럼 샤를리즈 테론이랑
데이트 약속 잡아줄 수 있어?
Maybe you can hook me up
with Charlize Theron.
농담 아닙니다 의원님
Funny, but I'm being
serious, sir.
나도 진담이야
샤를리즈 테론을 따먹고 싶어서 말야
No, I'm being serious, too.
I'd like to fuck her.
그런데 갑자기 나한테 왜 찝적대?
부통령 커피에 좆이라도 데였냐?
Why'd you leave anyway? You get stuck
with your dick in the veep's decaf?
우리 팀 모두
새출발을 할 필요가 있어서요
No, we just all need
new challenges.
자네 지금 "우리 팀 모두"라고 했나?
We? What, is the whole
team leaving?
- 아닙니다 의원님
- 존나 시발?!
- No, no. No, sir.
- Holy shit.
- 부통령 때려치우려는거구만
- 아뇨, 절대 아닙니다
- She's leaving the ticket.
- No, absolutely not.
부통이랑 나랑 거래했다고!
내가 2년 안에 상원의원이 되고
We had a fucking deal.
I make Senate in two years,
부통이랑 나랑 6년 뒤에
같이 대선에 출마하는거지
we run together
as a team in six.
- 네, 그랬었죠
- 나가서 모가지를 따 뒤져버려라 윌
- That was the deal.
- Why don't you fucking kill yourself, Will?
정확히 말씀드리죠 의원님,
부통령님은 사퇴한 뒤에
Let me be clear, sir. She may
be planning to run in six years
6년 뒤 대선에 출마할지도 몰라요
if she was leaving the ticket,
부통령님이 직접 그러겠다고
말씀하신 건 아니지만요
which I have not
actually said she will.
존나 감사합니다 드디어 멈췄네
Oh, fucking God,
thank you for stopping.
그거 아나?
You know what?
If I didn't already know
니가 언론 담당 보좌관을 존나게
못한다는걸 지금 나한테 입증한 셈이야
how shitty you are at your
job, you just proved it.
엄청난 소식이 있습니다 부통령님
I have some
very big news, ma'am.
나야말로 엄청난 소식이 있다
Well, I have huge news.
내 소식은 뉴스 1면감일걸?
In fact, I guarantee you that
my news is front-page news.
자네 소식은 한 6면쯤 되려나?
Your news is probably
more like a page six,
연예인 스캔들 찌끄레기급이겠지
Kardashian crap news.
대통령께서 이번 일로 인한
결말을 알게 된 뒤,
POTUS knows how this
is all going to end,
끝내 독약을 탄 음료수를
so he drank
the poisoned Kool-Aid
이 몹시 큰 파란 머그컵으로 원샷하셨어요
from my very big, blue mug.
- 뭐라고?
- 2년 뒤 대선에 재출마하지 않으실 거예요
- Huh?
- He isn't going to run again in two years.
진짜로?
Are you serious?
존나 로레알입니다
No, I'm Joan fucking Rivers.
진짜라고요
Of course I'm serious.
각 당 지도부 측에서
대통령의 연임 포기 의사를 알게 되면
Once the party leadership
figures out he's not gonna run,
탄핵 소동은
일단 잠재울 수 있게 되는 거죠
then all the impeachment bullshit
is just gonna fade away.
그러니까..
So, um--
왜 각하께서 직접 말씀하지 않고
자네가 말하는건가?
so why didn't he tell me this?
Why are you telling me this?
대통령께서 부통령 각하의
그 표정을 못 보시겠다는겁니다
Because he couldn't stomach
the look-- like that,
지금처럼 자제가 안되는
기뻐하는 얼굴 말이죠
just like that--
of unbridled joy.
벤, 나는 지금 울고 있는거야
Ben, I am crying
매우 깊은 내면 속에서 말이야
very quietly on the inside.
대통령 각하 무덤에다 대고
환희의 발레라도 하는 것 같으신데요
While in your mind you're doing
pirouettes on his grave.
왜 이래? 솔직히 자네도 좋잖아
Oh, don't tell me you're
not happy about this.
자네도 드디어 대통령한테서
벗어날 수 있게 된거라고!
You're finally
getting out of here.
제가 우울한건 제 보직 때문이 아녜요
Well, it's not the job
that's depressing.
원래 삶이 우울했을 뿐이지
Life is depressing.
가자꾸낭
Let's go.
아냐, 내가 직접 할게
No, I've got it.
I can do this.
괜찮아
I'm fine.
오호호호호호
앗싸!
Yes!
존나 씨발!!!!!!
Fuck! Gosh!
에헴
Ahem.
안녕하세요 수,
Hi, Sue.
매우 긴급한 사안이 있어서
부통령님을 즉시 뵈어야겠습니다
We'd like to see the vice president
as a matter of some urgency.
- 안돼요
- 좆까 옆문으로 들어갈테다
- No.
- Fuck this, I'm going in the side door.
들어가보세요
경호원들한테 모가지 꺾여보고싶으면
You do and Secret Service
might break your neck.
- 엄청 아프실텐데
- 그래? 부통령 각하!
- That would be a tragedy.
- Yeah? Ma'am.
- 오, 안녕 로저?
- 잠시 말씀 좀 나누죠?
- Oh, hi, Roger.
- Can we talk?
물론 괜찮지,
저기, 요거트 하나만 줄래?
Of course we can talk. Hey,
could I have my yogurt, please?
여기 있습니다
너무 빨리 드시지 마세요
Oh, here.
Don't eat it too fast.
왜 이래, 잔소리꾼처럼
Oh, stop it, Nervous Nelly.
나도 숟가락으로 떠먹을 만한 거
하나만 줘봐
All right, get me something
sloppy with a spoon to eat.
- 요거트 한 입 먹을래?
- 됐소이다
- Do you want some yogurt?
- No, thanks.
- 자네 혈색이 좋아보이는구만
- 고맙네그려
- You look good, by the way.
- Oh, thanks.
무슨 운동이라도 하나?
What, are you
working out or what?
그럼, 오랜 불안감(anxiety)으로
칼로리를 태우고 있어서(diet) 말이지
Yeah, I'm burning calories
with the old anxiety diet.
- 아,
- anxiet(anxiety+diet) 말이야
- Oh.
- You know, the anxiet.
심폐 운동을 하려면
제대로 된 심장이라도 달려 있어야 할텐데
If you want to get some cardio
exercise, you have to have a heart.
조금 불쾌한 소문을 듣자 하니
I heard a pretty lousy rumor
부통령께서 사임을 하겠다는 것같은데
that you're not running for
reelection with POTUS in two years.
- 그래?
- 정말 그게 사실이라면 안되는데
- Oh.
- And that would be disturbing
내가 주지사가 되려면
부통 당신이 필요해서 말이지
because I kind of need you
to run as VP again.
그 밀약이 유효해야
And then I get in the Senate
우리가 나중에 같이 손잡고
대선에 나갈 거 아닌가?
and then you and I
run together as a team.
- 그게 우리 밀약 조건이었잖아
- 물론, 그랬지
- Remember, that was the deal.
- Yeah, I remember that.
그런 소문은 어디서 들었나?
Where did you hear this rumor?
아, 빨강머리한테 들었지
Oh, I heard it from
the Gingerhead Man.
맥클린톡에 나오는
그 콧수염 허우대 말이야
The gash with the stash.
McLintock.
뭐? 진짜로?
What, are you kidding me?
마이크는 주둥아리가 재앙이야
그냥 잊어버려
Mike sees knowledge as the enemy.
Forget about that.
그럼 2년 남은 부통령직을
계속하겠다는 건가?
Then you are running with
the president in two years?
당연히 2년 더 하지
I am absolutely running
in two years.
그리고 2년 하고도 4년 뒤에는
re-election(선거)이지
(2년 더 부통령을 한 뒤 대선 출마하여 대통령이 되면
임기 말년에 대통령 연임을 위해 재출마하는 re-election)
And then four years
after that, reelection, baby.
re-election이라니 무슨 소리야?
What do you mean reelection?
그 때는 re-election이 아니라
election이지
(펄롱은 대통령의 연임 포기 의사를 모르기 때문에
6년 뒤의 선거는 그냥 election이 맞다고 생각함)
Not reelection.
Election at that time.
- 응, 맞아
- 너랑 나랑 같이 대선에 나가자는 거잖아
- Yep. Right.
- You and I election.
잠깐, 왜 re-election이라 한 거지?
Wait. But why did
you say reelection?
- 뭐라고?
- 분명히 re-election이라고 했잖아
- What?
- You said reelection.
뭔가 내가 모르는 꿍꿍이가
있는 것 같은데?
Which implies that perhaps
something else is going on.
election이라고 했잖아
뭘 잘못 들었나보네
I meant election.
You know what I meant.
- re-election이라고 했잖아?
- election이라고, 알겠어?
- But you said reelection.
- I meant election, okay?
"가연성"이나 "인화성"이나
그게 그거인것처럼
It's like saying
flammable or inflammable.
- 아무 의미 없는 거라고
- 내가 냄새라면 존나 잘 맡거든?
- It's the same thing.
- I smell a fucking rat.
- 왜 이래?
- 내가 직접 설명해주지
- Oh, stop it.
- I'll tell you what it is, too.
현 행정부에 뭔가 꿍꿍이가 있어
It's this whole administration.
내가 존나게 불을 질러 줄테다
And I'm gonna light a fire
under the whole thing.
그러면 뭐가 가연성이고
뭐가 인화성인지 금방 알 수 있겠지
Then we'll find out whether
it's flammable or inflammable.
가자 이 저능아새끼야
가자고
Come on, Wilbo Faggins,
let's go.
그래, 내 아름다운
보좌관들 어디 갔나?
Okay, where are my
beautiful veeple people?
여기 있구만
There's one.
I need my veeple
내 사람들이여 지금 당장
집무실로 집합해주세요
to come into my office, please.
J-드래곤이 왔어열
푸쳐핸접 하세열
Hey, it's J-Diddy.
Ladies get giddy.
- 조나, 부탁 하나만 들어줄래?
- 알겠습니다
- Jonah. Hey, listen, settle something for me.
- Okay.
fuck하는 거랑
(여행)나가는 것 좋아하나?
You like to have sex
and you like to travel?
- 그럼요 부통령님
- 그럼 (Fuck off) 해버려
- Yes, ma'am.
- Then you can fuck off.
하지만 부통령께서 저를
언제든지 찾을 수 있도록 대기하겠습니다
But I shall be right here
if you need me.
굳건한 떡갈나무처럼 말이죠
그게 무엇을 뜻하냐면-
Like the mighty oak
that stands for-- ma'am.
전파할 사항이 있어
I have something to say.
이제 무슨 말일지 정말 모르겠네요
I've literally no idea
what you're gonna say.
난 사퇴 안해
대통령이 재선을 포기할거야
I'm not leaving.
POTUS is leaving.
연임을 포기할거래
He's not gonna run
for a second term.
- 내가 대선에 출마한다!!
- 세상에나!
- I'm gonna run.
- Oh, my God!
- 대통령 선거에 출마할거라고!
- 아싸!!
- I'm gonna run for president!
- Oh, yeah!
- 엄청난 소식이네요!
- 정말 예상도 못했는데
- That's awesome.
- I did not see that coming.
설리나 마이어가
진짜배기 게임에 도전합니다! 빠밤!
Selina Meyer,
she deals 'em fire. Bam!
존나게 달까지 날아가보자고요!
Boom! Let's go
to the fucking moon!
여차하면 실직자 되서
배에서 잘 뻔했는데
I was this close
to living on my boat.
- 세상에나! 정말..
- 축하드립니다 부통령님
- Oh, my God. I'm just--
- Congratulations, ma'am.
어 자네 잠깐..
Can you give me
자리 좀 비워주지 않겠나?
some time with my core team?
- 브르..
- 에드요!
- Um, Br-- Br-
- Ed.
- 브레드?
- 알겠습니다
- Bre-- Ed.
- Of course.
방금 소리 들어보니 저 빼고
뭔가 중요한 걸 이야기한 모양인데
I feel as though I may
have missed something.
저도 알아야 한다면 여기-
If you need to
fill me in on that--
방금 저기 무슨 일이죠?
Hey, what happened in there?
당신이 저 방 안에 없던 것을
They're celebrating
자축하고 있어요
because you weren't in there.
이제 악셀만 밟으면 돼요
Gears are already turning.
- 자네 머리 위에 전구를 본 것 같아
- 짠!
- I see a lightbulb above your head.
- Bing!
이제 다들 들어봐
Okay, now listen, so...
새 직업을 구할 필요 없어
you guys don't need
to take other jobs.
나랑 끝까지 함께하는거야
You're here with me.
저는 스카우트 제의를
좀 많이 받았습니다만
Uh, I've accepted
a number of posts.
- "좀 많이"?
- 지금까지 네 개요
- Did you say a number?
- Currently four.
그거 전부 취소할 거지?
Wow. You're gonna
cancel them, right?
아, 물론입니다
Oh, clearly.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
저는 들어온 모든 제의를 거절했습니다
제겐 부통령님 뿐입니다
I've said no to everything, ma'am.
I am here for you.
- 좋아
- 부통령님,
- Good.
- Hey, ma'am.
저도 제의를 좀 받았어요
I took a job also.
- 너는 예외잖아 개리
- 알아요
- I didn't mean you, Gary.
- I know.
무슨 자리인데?
What job?
제 여친 데이나랑 사업을 하기로 했어요
I'm going into
business with Dana
D&G 치즈 수출 사업이요
and we're doing
D&G Cheese Overseas.
- 치즈라고?
- 네, 수출로요
- Cheese?
- And it's overseas.
잠깐만, 지금 날 버리고
썩은 우윳덩이나 만지겠다는거야?
Wait a minute. You're
choosing dead milk over me?
그렇게 말씀하시면 안되죠
썩은 우윳덩이라뇨
No, don't say that.
That's not true.
여친한테 가서
동업 안 할 거라고 말해야지
Well, you're just gonna have to
tell her you're not gonna do that.
안돼요, 말 못해요
I can't.
I can't tell her that.
왜 못해?
여친이 무서워?
Why not?
Are you scared of her?
- 네
- 그래
- Yeah.
- Okay.
개리, 너는 여친에 잡혀 사는
Gary, you cannot let this woman
유약한 남자가 아니잖아, 안 그래?
have control over you, okay?
정말이야, 네 스스로의 의견을
관철시킬 줄 알아야지
Seriously, you have got
to stick up for yourself.
넌 내 사람이잖아
You gotta work for me.
맞아요, 맞는데
여친이 많이 무섭단 말이예요
Right. Right.
She scares me a lot.
알았어, 여친 이리 데려와
내가 얘기해볼게
All right, call her in
and I'm gonna talk to her.
- 알겠지?
- 네, 알겠습니다
- Okay?
- Okay, yeah. Got it.
부통령님 30분 뒤에
과학 전시회에 가셔야 합니다
Ma'am, science fair
in 30 minutes.
그래, 네가 그것 처리하고
너는 개리 문제 좀 해결해줘, 알겠지?
Okay, you go deal with that
and you cover for Gary, okay?
그 리바이어던 가방만큼이나 날 믿지?
You trust me
with that Leviathan?
부통령님, 제가
블랙베리 폰을 거기에 놓고나왔-
Uh, ma'am, I left
my BlackBerry in--
그래, 이제 과학 전시회
일정을 처리해야 하는데
Okay, now listen, I got
this science fair thing.
거기 현장에서 할 연설을
So I want to make my speech
- 좀 더 대선 출마처럼 적극적으로 하자고
- 알겠습니다
- a little bit more presidential.
- Yeah.
마릴린 먼로처럼 쩔게,
Like I'm Marilyn Monroe,
그리고 존 F 케네디 좆까라 할 정도로!
just JFK the fuck out of me.
- 아, 제게 아이디어가 있습니다
- 정말?
- Ooh, I got something.
- You do?
- 정말입니다, 아이디어가 있다고요
- 환상적이구만
- Yeah, I do. I got something.
- Fantastic.
저만 내버려두고 이야기하시는데
뭔가 중요한게-
I'm just completely
in the dark. If--
난 앤드류한테 전화해야겠어
I'm gonna go call Andrew.
Mm-mm-mm.
- 부통령님?
- 아냐냐냐, 그냥 그 돈 때문에 그러는거야
- Uh-- uh--
- No, no, no, it's all about crazy money, Ame.
앤드류가 그 돈을 갖고 있으니
He's got the crazy money
나는 그걸 선거 자금으로 이용해야지
and I'm crazy enough
to go get it.
정말 선거에 한한 거죠?
As long as it's strictly business.
앤디? 나야
Andy? It's me.
라라고
It's Lee.
일로 좀 올래?
Can you come here?
컼컼컼컼컼컼ㅋㅋ컼컼
오, 왔구나 자기
Oh, there he is.
그만 좀 뎁혀!
치즈 다 녹을라!
Hey, quit being so hot. You're
gonna melt all my cheese.
- 안뇽 자기
- 안녕, 자기
- Hi, you.
- Hi, sweetie. Hi.
무슨 문제 있어?
Hey, what's wrong?
내가 자기한테 섹드립 쳐보라고
했을때처럼 얼굴이 굳어있네
You look like you did when
I asked you to talk dirty.
- "삽입, 아, 아니 사랑해"라고 버벅거렸잖아
- 쉬쉿, 알았어, 알았어
- You were just like, "I'm in you right now."
- Shh. I know, I know.
잠깐만, 잠깐만,
할 얘기가 있어
Stop, stop. I wanted to talk
to you about something.
부통령께서 사임 안 하신대
Selina's gonna stay.
부통령 문제는 이미 끝났잖아
Okay. Well, that
ship has sailed.
자기랑 나랑은 함께 하기로 한
페코리노 치즈 사업이 있고
You're on the good ship
Pecorino now.
그게, 나도 부통령님하고
계속 함께하려고
Yeah, I'm gonna stay,
too, I think.
- 안돼, 안돼
- 좀 들어봐
- No. No.
- Okay, listen--
- 토스카노는 어디 있죠?
- D12에
- Where's the Toscano?
- It's at D12.
바로 저기 있지?
부통령님은 날 필요로 해
That's right over there, okay?
She needs me.
나는 부통령님의 중추신경계나
다름없는 중요한 사람이야
It's like I'm her
central nervous system.
왜 그래, 가방 셔틀이라면
자기 말고도 차고 넘쳤어
Honey, she'll get another
bag bunny, I just know it.
브렛, 거기가 아니고 아랫쪽이야
그건 Sardo잖아
No, Brett, it's further down.
That's the Sardo, buddy.
나는 가방 셔틀이 아니거든?
Okay, I'm not a bag bunny.
나는 부통령님의 소울메이트나
다름없는 사람이야
It's like I'm Selina's
soul mate over there.
- 그딴걸 말이라고 싸고 있어 지금?
- 화 난거 다 알아
- Okay, I love the stinking shit out of you, Gary.
- I know you do.
부통령이 널 아낀다고 생각해?
넌 아무 것도 아닌 놈이야
She doesn't love you, okay?
She doesn't care.
- 각하께선 날 아껴
- 넌 그냥 부통령 꼭두각시나 다름없어
- She does care.
- You're just a guy that does a job for her.
- 그렇지 않아
- 누가 더 중요해?
- That's not true.
- Who's more important to you?
- 나야? 부통령이야?
- 그런 식으로 물으면 대답할 방법이-
- Me or her?
- Okay, that choice, there's no way--
블랙 트러플 종류는 없나요?
Do we have any
with black truffle?
F15에 있어? F15에
That's F15.
Okay? F15.
그런 식으로 극단적으로 물으면
어떻게 선택을 할 수가 있겠니?
Listen, the choice you're giving me
between you and her, that's impossible.
죄송한데 블랙 트러플 말고
화이트 트러플은 어디 있죠?
Sorry, not black truffle.
I meant white truffle.
블랙 트러플 옆에 있다고!
That's next to
the black truffle, okay.
니 귓구녕에 똥이라도 찼어?
What the fuck is wrong
with you, Brett?
여기가 무슨 축구장이야?
넓지도 않은 곳인데!
This is not a big place, is it?
It's not a big place.
죄송해요, 제가 혹시 비켜드릴까요?
I'm sorry. Would you
guys like some space?
- 그래!
- 아니! 거기 그대로 있어
- Yeah!
- No! Stay right where you are.
알았어, 부통령께서
자기랑 얘기 좀 하재
Okay, listen,
she wants to talk to you.
- 부통령님께서 직접 설명해주시겠대
- 알았어
- She wants to explain this to you.
- Fine.
- 내 말 좀 들어줘
- 알았어 가 줄게
- Okay? Please?
- I'll go.
널 위해서 부통령 모가지 쯤이야
꺾어버릴 수 있지 뭐
I'm not afraid to fight for you, Gary.
That's the truth.
아냐냐냐냐냐 그게 아니고
No, no, no.
Bah, bah, bah, bah.
싸움은 정말 안돼, 알겠지?
Let's literally
not fight, all right?
알겠지? 치즈 맛있네
Okay?
That's good cheese.
에이미, 실제상황이라고
Amy, this is really happening.
자기, 방금 전에 내가 한 말은 잊어
You know, listen,
just ignore that earlier me.
"초원의 집"어쩌고 했던 개소리 말이야
The "Little House
on the Prairie" bullshit.
다시 소식이 들어왔는데,
내 일자리도 무사하고
No, updated me,
totally career focused
장차 백악관으로 갈 수도 있겠어!
and shooting
for the White House.
물론 나는 언제나 자기 곁에서,
뒤에서도 함께할 거야
Of course, and I am
right behind/beside you.
자기는 대통령 참모총장이 되는거고
You, Chief of Staff
to the president,
나는 자기의 침대총장이되는거지
me, chief of sexiness
and spooning.
그래, 그런데 아까 말했듯이
지금 집중해야 할 것은..
Yeah, but as I said,
the focus right now
has got to be...
_
에이미, 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
Hey, Amy, can I talk to you about something?
좀 재앙급 사고야
Accidental dick move.
과학 전시회에서 부통령님이
연설할 연설문 대본을 급하게 쓰느라
I had to write Selina's speech
for the science fair so fast
실수로 청 주지사한테 써준 걸
대본에 그대로 복사-붙여넣기한것같아
that I think I plagiarized a
speech that I wrote for Chung.
이건 부통령님 대본 복사본인데
So here's Selina's hard copy
청 주지사 연설한게
벌써 유투브에 올라와 있어
and Chung's is already
up on his YouTube.
저는 후아니타라는 이름의
젊은 여성을 만나뵈었습니다.
I met a young woman
name Juanita.
- 이 부분이야
- "미국이 저에게 무엇인지는 중요치 않아요
- Oh, here's the bit.
- It's not about what America means to me.
제가 미국에게 무엇인지가
중요한 거예요"라더군요
It's what I mean to America.
미국은 국민들이 없으면
아무 것도 아니게 되니까요
Because America would be
nothing without Americans.
니가 저걸 썼다고?
Jesus, you wrote this shit?
Yeah, it's like
a noun-verb gumbo.
후아니타는 내가 지어낸 이름이야
부통령님한테도 똑같은 레파토리로 써줬고
So it's the fictitious girl.
I gave her the same girl.
물론 후아니타 대신
아니타라고 쓰긴 했지만
Although I did change it
from Juanita to Anita.
존나게 대단한 계획이시네
Oh, that's a brilliant plan.
미국 대신 미역국이라고 쓰지 그랬어?
빨리 마이크한테 전화해야겠다
Why don't you change America to Shmamerica?
Yeah, I'm calling Mike.
내가 해봤어,
그런데 음성사서함으로 넘어가
No, I already tried him. It
went straight to voice mail.
저는 아니타라는 이름의
이 소녀 과학자를 만나봤습니다.
I met this young
scientist named Anita.
- 그래서 제가 대화를 해봤죠-
- 충전기 있니?
- And I said to her...
- You got a charger?
- 조용히 하세요! 연설 듣고 있잖아요
- 알겠다 꼬마야
- Shh, I'm trying to watch.
- Okay, champ.
그래서 아니타가 말하길
"과학이 저에게 무엇인지는 중요치 않아요"
...and she said, "It's not
what science means to me,
제가 과학에게 무엇인지가 중요한 거예요
라더군요
it's what I mean
to science."
여기부터 보죠, 이건 애완동물을 위한
소셜미디어 클라우드 맵이고요
Let's do this one first. This is a
mappable social media cloud for pets.
- 어머나! 정말 멋지구나!
- 홈런입니다
- Oh, I'm impressed with that.
- Home run.
내가 한 마디 하지
딱 세 가지 단어로
Listen, let me tell you something.
Three words--
전당 대회, 경선, 선거자금
caucus, primary, money.
- 알겠지?
- 원대하시네요
- Right?
- Go big.
아니다, 한 단어만 더 추가하자
선거자금 또 한번 강조! 알겠지?
No, four words-- money again.
Right?
우리에게 제일 필요한건
엄청나게 많은 선거자금이야
'Cause that's what we need.
Mike, we need a lot of money.
여기는 레이챌과 에리카입니다
부통령 각하
This is Rachel and Erica
over here, ma'am.
- 어머나? 이게 뭐니?
- (개미 키부츠(공동사회)예요)
- Oh, wow, what is this?
- It's an ant kibbutz.
정말 너무 잘 만들었구나
Okay. I would love
to look at that.
아, 또 하나 생각난게 있어
Oh, and I just had a thought.
- 아이오와의 그 스테이크 프라이 집 기억나?
- 물론이죠
- Remember that Iowa steak fry thing?
- Mm-hmm.
- 거기도 가는거야
- 네
- We need to go to that.
- Yeah.
정말이야, 거기는
돈 많은 사람들이 엄청 많아!
Seriously, 'cause there's
a lot of money there.
- 그리고 스테이크도요!
- 맞아! 그것도 너무 맛있지
- And steak.
- And steak. I love it.
부통령님이 이걸 보고
무슨 생각하시는지 알 것 같아요
So, I know what you're thinking,
Madam Vice President.
- 정말? 그러니?
- 사방이 막힌 장소, 맞죠?
- You do? Uh-oh.
- A confined space, right?
하지만 개미들에게 인도적인 환경이랍니다
But it's a humane environment.
위에서 보니 개미같아보이는구나!
Well, from up here,
they look like ants.
농담이란다
That's a joke.
- 개미니까!
- 이 쪽으로 오시죠 각하
- Because they are ants.
- This way, ma'am.
- 이건 로보트 종류라고 하는데
- 저게 로보트라고?
- This is some kind of robot.
- Really? That's it?
- 실례합니다
- 이봐 이 느림보 영감탱이!
- Would you excuse me?
- Hey, Joe fucking Slow.
전화기는 어디다 쳐박아놓고
받질 않아요?
You ever think about
answering your phone?
진정해! 충전기 잃어버렸다고
충전기 있냐?
Chill out. I lost my charger.
You got one?
여기 널리고 널린 발명왕 꼬마한테
충전기 하나 만들어달라 할 생각도 못 했어요?
You're at a science fair. One of these
kids could build you a charger.
- 왜 그러는데?
- 벤이 계속 연락했는데 닿질 않아서요
- What's the problem?
- Ben's been trying to get in touch with the veep all day.
부통령님이 바쁘셔서
All right, well, she's busy.
미안하구나 토드
잠깐만 실례하자
Sorry there, Todd.
Just real quick.
- 그런가?
- 나라 문제라서,
- Oh.
- Matters of state.
네, 지금 부통령님 바꿔드리겠습니다
벤이예요
Sir, yes, I have the vice
president for you. It's Ben.
- 잠깐 좀 비켜주겠니?
- 여보세요 벤, 좀 어떤가?
- Give her a little space.
- Hi, Ben. How's it going?
펄롱이 언론에다 대고
개소리를 싸제끼고 있어요
Furlong has been spraying
all over town
대통령이 연임 안 하겠다는 걸
부통령한테서 들었다면서 말이죠
that you think
POTUS is gonna quit.
뭐? 그 트롤같은 광대새끼한테
그런 말 한 적 없는데?
What? I didn't say anything
to that crusty ass clown.
내가 말이 좀 헛나왔을 지도 모르지만..
I might have mixed up
a couple words, but...
어쨌든 대통령께서 연임을 포기 못하겠다고
생각을 바꾸셨어요
Well, now POTUS can't say that he
won't be running for reelection
연임을 포기하면 마치 쫓겨나는 것처럼
보일거라고 말이죠
because it'll look like
he's being pushed out.
그래서 척추도 뼈도 없는
So now our spineless,
흐물흐물 젤리 영감탱이가
연임을 하겠답니다!
flip-floppy fuckbag
is staying.
- 시발.
- 괜찮은겁니까?
- Oh, boy.
- Is everything okay?
열이 차 올라서 이 과학덕후 집합소에
불이라도 지르기 전에 빨리 여길 떠야겠어
I've got to get out of here before
I set fire to one of these nerds.
- 알겠습니다, 어서 가죠
- 그거 제 폰이거든요
- Okay, okay, let's go.
- That's my phone.
- 고마워요, 고마워요
- 부통령 여사님!
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Madam Vice President.
- 안된다
- 미안하구나, 부통령께선 너희들을 정말 좋아하는데
- No.
- We're so sorry. She really likes it,
부통령께서 급한 일이 생겨서 말이야
but unfortunately she's
out of time, you guys.
여기 이 키 큰 오빠하고
못다한 얘기를 해보려무나
But this man right here
is gonna take over for her.
말아먹지 마라
여론 잘못 자극했다간 종치는 수가 있어!
Don't fuck this up. This is a public
relations nightmare waiting to happen.
(그냥 다 해주겠다고 해)
고마워 얘들아
Promise them everything.
Thank you, kids.
_
각하, 지금-
Ma'am, are you--
(아아아ㅏㅏㅏㅏ아아아ㅏㅏㄱ!!!!!)
주지사께서 여기를 좋아하실 것 같았죠
I thought you'd
like this spot.
워싱턴 DC에서 비공식적으로
도움을 주고받을 때 만나는 인기 장소죠
DC's current go-to place for
these off-the-record meets.
좋은 선택이야. 내 군 시절에 쓰던
말을 빌자면 "언더 더 레이더"라고도 하지
Good choice. Under the radar as
we used to say in the military.
네, 다른 사람들도
그렇게 표현하더군요
Yeah, I think other
people say that, too.
이건 진실과, 미국 국민 앞에 했던
It's about loyalty
to the truth.
서약에 대한 문제입니다
And to the American people.
펄롱이랑 도일이 대통령한테
총부리를 들이미는구만
Furlong and Doyle have turned
their guns on the president.
아군의 포격이 따로 없구만
That's the worst kind
of friendly fire.
아군이라기보다는 적군이겠지만
The unfriendly kind.
네, 그리고 주지사님,
드릴 말씀이 있는데,
Yeah, oh, Danny, I just
want to let you know,
주지사님이 발언하셨던 일화 중에서
one of your anecdotes
may have accidentally
제가 작성했던 부통령 연설문이
실수로 흘러들어간 것 같아서 말이죠
made its way into
a veep speech via me.
그 일에 대해서 눈감아 주시면
대단히 감사하겠습니다
And I'd really appreciate it if
you could let this one slide.
부통령이 내 껄 베꼈다고?
완벽한데?
Selina's a plagiarist?
That's perfect.
나한테 핵폭탄 스위치를 안겨주는구만
You just handed me
a silver bullet.
자네도 알다시피
내가 그런 거라면 아주 잘 쏘지
And as you know,
I'm a good shot.
부통령을 거짓말쟁이라고 발언하는 건
조금 유보해주심이 어떨까 하는데요
I might back away, though,
from calling her a liar.
어쨌든 주지사님도 후아니타라는
여자를 실제로 만나뵌 건 아니잖아요
After all, you didn't really meet
anyone named Juanita who said that.
아니, 만났는데?
목소리가 어땠냐면
No, I did. As I recall,
it went something like...
"칭 주지사뉨? 나 와써요
아메리까에 일하러
"Mr. Ching,
I come to America to work.
나 집에 돈 보낸다, 그런데
아메리까에서 사는거 힘드러요 너무"
I send money home, but life
here is so hard for me."
성대모사도 걸출하시군요
I didn't know you did voices.
_
수, 이리 와
Sue, come here.
- 댄은?
- 밖에 나가 있어요
- Where's Dan?
- He stepped out.
어, 으흠
Um, ahem.
대통령이
연임 안 하기로 한 걸 취소했어
POTUS has decided
that he is staying,
결국 재선을 할거라는 말이지
and he is going to seek
reelection after all.
물론 사퇴할 이유가 없겠죠
Of course he wants to stay.
그 아가리 좀 닥-
Could you just not...
아무튼 대통령이
다음 대선에도 나간다 하니
So he's running
for a second term,
나는 다음 대선에 못 나가겠지
which means I won't be
running for a first term.
그러니 내가 부통령을 할 이유가 없어
난 사퇴할 거야
So there's no point in my staying.
I'm just gonna leave.
- 대통령이 정말 마음을 바꿨다고요?
- 그래
- So he changed his mind again?
- Yeah.
그 분 머리 속에 무슨
모리스 에셔라도 살고 있나
(난해한 그림을 그린 초현실주의 화가)
Jesus, the inside of his head
must be like an Escher drawing.
부통령님, 부군께서 오셨습니다
Ma'am, Andrew
is here to see you.
엎친 데 덮친 격이구만
Oh, good, more hurt
and disappointment.
드릴 말씀이 하나 더 있습니다
There is one
other thing that--
실망을 안겨드려 대단해 죄송하지만
and I'm so sorry
to let you down,
저는 부통령님 곁에 머물고자 합니다.
but I'm gonna stay with Selina.
내가 자네를 고용할지 말지를
You think you get to decide
자네가 쥐고 흔든다고 생각하는가?
on whether or not I hire you?
네 대타는 차고 넘친단다 댄
There are plenty
of Dans out there, Dan.
한번 뒤돌아봐
Look around.
미안하구나 꼬마야
Sorry, kid.
방금 꼬마라고 했어요?
Hey, don't call me kid, okay?
첫째, 주지사님은
지미 카그니가 아녜요, 알겠어요?
I mean, A: you're not
Jimmy Cagney, all right?
둘째, 주지사님이나 나나
나이 차이 좆도 없거든요?
And B: we're practically
the same fucking age.
나이 똑같이 쳐먹은 놈이
파리처럼 여기저기 부비고 다니는게 자랑이다
Then it must really hurt to know how
much more I've achieved in life.
이 몸은 참전 용사이자
유력한 차기 대통령 후보라고
Decorated veteran.
President-in-waiting.
아, 그러셔요? 이거 보여요?
이거 보이냐고요?
Oh, okay. Do you see this?
See this right here?
세계에서 제일 큰 첼로로
좆까 좆까 좆을까세요~를 연주 중인데
You know what this is? This is me playing
"Fuck You" on the world's biggest cello.
자기 손으로 자기 미래에
돌이킬 수 없는 폭탄을 터트리는구만
Oh, I think someone just suicide
bombed their own future.
그거 알아? 당신이 전쟁 어쩌구를
나불거릴때마다 1달러씩 받았다면
God, you know, if I had a dollar for every
time you mentioned that goddamn war,
그 돈으로 탱크를 하나 사서
당신 존나 잘난 면상을 깔아뭉갰을거야
I would buy a tank and I would
blow your fat fucking head off.
와, 미안하구만 댄
Wow. Well, I'm sorry, Dan.
자네를 버려두고 가게 되서
안타깝지만, 조만간 다시 보지
I hate to leave a man down,
but I'll see you around.
보낸 이 : 에이미
"부통령님 사퇴하신대
대통령은 연임한다고 하고"
주지사님, 주지사님!!
Danny.
Danny, hey.
존나 씨발 장난해?
Are you fucking kidding me?
날 여기까지 데려와 놓고
빈손으로 가라는 거야?
You brought me
over here for nothing?
지금 상황에 위로는 못할망정
그걸 말이라고 하는거야?
Are you really talking
to me like this right now?
- 내 일을 다 쌩까고 왔는데!
- 재수가 완전 꼬였다고!
- I have shit to do.
- I am in a bad way.
정말로 말도 안되게
재앙급 탈선이야!
Honestly, it's so out of line.
- 존나게 탈선이라고!
- 정말이예요
- It's so out of line.
- It is.
워싱턴 DC에서는 누구한테나
뒤통수를 후려맞는 법이야
You get fucked
by everybody in DC--
친구, 적,
your friends, your enemies,
동료, 그리고 씨발놈의 가족까지!
your colleagues,
your fucking family.
그게 워싱턴 DC라는 도시야
That's Washington, DC, for you.
DC! "드"럽게 "씨"발같은 놈들
DC-- District of Cunts.
부통령님, 과학 전시회에서 보신
샐리, T.J., 폴 군 기억나시죠?
Ma'am, you remember
Sally, T.J., and Paul.
우리 덕후 친구들이예요
아, 악의는 아니었습니다
This is my nerd herd. And I
mean that affectionately.
조나, 여기는 통제구역이거든?
Jonah, this is
a restricted area.
51구역같은 곳이라고
더더욱 제한구역이란 점만 빼고
(미 공군 비밀기지)
We're like Area 51
except more restricted.
- 조나, 잠깐 나랑 얘기 좀 하지?
- 네
- Jonah, can you come here just for a second?
- Yeah.
지금같은 상황에 나보고
꼬마애들까지 상대해주라는거야?
Do you want to fill me in as
to what's going on right now?
물론입니다 각하, 부통령님께서
과학전시회 행사를 무단 취소하셔서요
Yes, ma'am. Your abrupt
exit from the science fair.
마이크는 언론들에 해명을 하고 있으니
각하께서 아이들에게 백악관 투어를 해주셔야겠어요
Mike needed a PR fix, so you have to
give these guys a West Wing tour.
- 뭐라고?
- 저기, 각하?
- What?
- Uh, ma'am.
얼른 내보내야 해
This has got to stop.
대통령님께서 부통령 각하를
만나뵈러 오신답니다
You should be aware that
the president is on his way.
얘들아, 저기 의자에 가서
좀 앉아있을래?
Hey, why don't we go sit
on these chairs for a second?
뭐라고? 대통령님이 오신다고?
What did you say? The
president is coming here?
- 예
- 왜? 한번도 행차한 적도 없는 사람이?
- Yes.
- Why? He never comes here.
저도 모릅니다, 저도 아는 게 없어요
I don't know. Information-wise,
I am becalmed.
대통령 각하께서 오신다고요?
The president is coming here?
개리! 네 여친이 방금 보안검색대를 통과했대
뭐 이런 대혼란이 다 있어!
Gary, Dana just cleared security.
This is anarchy.
부통령님, 지금 제 여친을
만나보실 수 있으신가요?
Hey, ma'am, is now a bad
time to talk to Dana?
- 아니!
- 알겠습니다, 제가 직접 조절하죠
- Yeah!
- Okay, let me just go fix that.
제가 알아서 할게요
I'll fix that.
- 안녕 안녕!
- 나랑 결혼할 개리찡!
- Hey. Hey.
- Gary who I'm gonna marry.
나의 피앙세!
Fiancee in the house.
Ooh, ooh!
미안하지만 지금은 때가 아냐 자기,
This is not a good time, baby.
페코리노 듀오 그란데 치즈
샘플까지 가져왔다고!
I brought the Pecorino
Duo Grande sampler.
- 직접 갈아내서!
- 알았어, 치즈는 내가 직접 전해드릴게
- Shaved and grated.
- Okay, I'll just give this to her.
왜 그러는데?
부통령이 나 만나기 싫대?
But why?
Oh, my God, is it Selina?
부통령이 나 싫어하는거지?
Right? She doesn't
like me, is that it?
- 각하께선 널 좋아해
- 그럼 뭔데?
- She loves you.
- Then what is it?
쉿!
Shh, shh.
- 대통령이 오고 계셔
- 어머나!
- POTUS is coming.
- Oh, my God!
경호인원이 엄청 많이 올 거고
각하는 수많은 외부인에 둘러싸이는걸 싫어하셔
There's a lot of security and he
doesn't like a lot of people around.
대통령께 우리 치즈를 전해드려야겠다
트위터에 올리면 대박날거야
He should get the basket. Right?
We'll get him to tweet about it.
엄청난 화제가 될거야!
대박 터지겠지
It'll be great publicity.
You know I'm right.
날 해고하려고 온 거겠지?
Is he gonna drop me
from the ticket?
- 그런거지? 완전 화 나셨을거야
- 저도 모르겠습니다
- Is that what's going on? He's gone postal.
- I have no idea.
- 부통령님
- 왜?
- Ma'am.
- What?
좀 진정하셔야겠어요
You've got to mello yellow.
충고하지 마!
Don't tell me not to panic.
나도 어떻게 하는지 안다고!
I know how to freak out, okay?
다들 좀 쳐 앉아봐!
Everybody can just
shut the shit up.
- 존나 생각 좀 하게!
- 알겠습니다
- I got to think.
- Okay.
- 설리나 상태가 어떨진 잘 알죠
- 앤드류, 말 걸지 마시죠
- We know what she's like.
- Andrew, don't talk to me.
부통령님, 애들은 어떻게 할까요-
Ma'am, should I get Jonah
to get the kids--
조나보고 얼른 내보내라 할게요
I'll get Jonah
to get the kids out.
조나! 아이들 좀
내 방으로 옮겨놔
Jonah, why don't you put
the kids in my office?
- 마이크! 마이크!
- 대통령께서 오고 계시나요?
- Mike. Mike.
- Is the president coming?
- 마이크! *6
- 알겠습니다 각하, 갑니다
- Mike! Mike! Mike! Mike! Mike! Mike!
- Ma'am, I'm coming.
- 왔어요, 왔다고요
- 이리 와
- I'm here. I'm here.
- Come here.
- 성명을 준비해야 해
- 알겠습니다
- We got to make a statement.
- Okay.
대통령이 날 부통령직에서 해고하려고
직접 여기까지 찾아오는 것 같아
Because I think POTUS is coming
here to kick me off the ticket.
그래서 대통령보다
내가 먼저 발표를 해야 해
And I've got to make a statement
saying I'm leaving the ticket
부통령직을 사임할 거라는 발표 말이야
내가 대통령한테 해고당할 수는 없지!
before he drops me from it. I've got to
jump before we get stabbed in the back.
- 대니 청 주지사가 발표를 하고 있어요
- 뭐?
- Danny Chung is making an announcement.
- What?
저는 미국 육군으로
복무하게 되어 영광이었고
I was proud to serve
in the military.
주지사로 뽑히게 된 것도
영광으로 생각합니다
I'm proud to serve
as a governor.
오늘 저는 대선 준비위원회를
구성하고 있다는 것을 밝힙니다
Today I've set up
an exploratory committee
- 2년 뒤에 있을 대선에 대비하여-
- 좋아
- to look into whether in a couple of years...
- Okay.
제가 주지사를 넘어 보다 큰 자리에서
미국 국민께 봉사하기 위하여-
...I might be of use serving
at an even higher level.
부통령이 널 행복하게 해주든?
나는 널 행복하게 해주는데 말이야
Does she make you happy?
Because I make you happy.
물론 자기는 내 행복이지
Of course you make
me happy, baby.
- 여기서 나가주셔야겠습니다
- 뭐야 이건?
- Ma'am, we're gonna have to ask you to leave.
- What is this?
대체 무슨 일이예요?
Oh, my God.
What's going on?
오늘 집에 돌아와서 얘기해!
We are gonna talk about this
when we get home.
- 자기는 내 다이아몬드같은 존재야
- 나는 존나 다이아몬드 원석이라고!
- You are my diamond.
- I am a diamond in the rough.
- 나도 알아!
- 그 손 못 치워?!
- I know you're a diamond.
- Get your hands off me.
이렇게 하는거야
I know what I'm gonna do.
청 주지사의 반대 진영으로 출마하는거야
I'm gonna run against Chung.
알겠지? 나는 부통령직을 사퇴하고
Okay? I'm gonna take
myself off the ticket.
청 주지사, 현 대통령
모두의 반대진영에서 출마할 거야
I'll run against Chung
and I'll run against POTUS.
정치계의 대학살이 시작될거야
It'll be like
a political massacre.
정신 차리세요 부통령님!
지금 혼란스러우셔서 이성을 잃으셨어요
Quit freaking out. You need
to get your head together.
무슨 소리야? 대통령은
당장 몇초 내로 여기 올 거라고
What do you mean? The president's
gonna be here any second.
이것봐요 봐요*4!
Lookie, lookie, lookie, lookie.
- 부통령님 드리려 가져왔어요
- 뭐?
- This is for you.
- What?
페코리노 치즈에서 드리는
호의의 선물이랍니다!
It's like a Pecorino
peace offering.
넌 또 어디에 총을 맞았길래
이 지랄이야?
What the crippling fuck
is going on with you?
- 제 여친 여기서 빼냈어요
- 얼른 여기서 나가기나 해
- I got rid of Dana.
- You've got to get out of here.
- 빨리 나가라고!
- 대통령님 소식입니다!
- Get out of here.
- I have POTUS incoming!
- 대통령님 소식입니다!
- 빨리 발표문 만들어 마이크
- I have POTUS incoming!
- Make a statement, Mike.
- 무슨 발표문이요?
- 모두 다!
- About what? About what?
- Everything.
네가 생각할 수 있는
모든 것들을 다 끌어모아서 써!
All possible statements
that you can even think of.
알겠습니다, 빨리 대령해드립죠
Okay, I'll come up
with something.
- 대통령께 인사드리러 가죠
- 날 무슨 미친년마냥 취급하지 말라고
- Let's go say hi to POTUS.
- Don't talk to me like I'm a crazy person.
그러려는 거 아니었어요
실수였어요
I didn't mean to.
It came out weird.
길을 트시오! 대통령 납시오!
길을 트시오!
Make a hole, yo. POTUS
coming through. Make a hole.
대통령님이 아니시잖아요?
You're not the president.
너도 저스틴 비버가 아니잖니
스포츠머리 꼬마야?
No, but you're not Justin
Bieber either, are you, sport?
각하, 대통령께서 오셨습니다
Ma'am.
POTUS is here.
어디에?
Where?
내 눈 안 보이는데
무슨 피규어 장난감으로 축소된거니?
Has he been miniaturized?
저 옆방에 와계십니다
He's right in that room.
만나뵈실 준비가 되셨습니까?
Would you care to join him
in your office?
으으..
Uh...
- 나 이러다 실신하는 거 아니겠지?
- 아녜요*3
- Am I about to get whacked?
- No, no, no.
다시 만나뵈어 영광이었습니다
몸 조리 잘 하세요!
No, it's good to see you again.
Take care.
대통령님께서 보고싶어하시잖아
얼른 들어가봐
Your boss wants to see you.
Don't keep him waiting.
무슨 일이예요?
What's going on here?
백악관 직원 총집합이라도 한 거예요?
Is it Bring a Disparate
Person to Work Day?
부통령께서 정통으로
헤드샷을 맞으러 가셨고
Uh, Selina is about to get a
Potal bullet through the head
너는 이제 1분 뒤에
실업자 및 노숙자가 될 거야
and you are all about to be
unemployed and homeless.
에이미, 넌 걱정 안 해도 돼
우리 집에서 재워줄게
But, Amy, I don't want you to worry.
You can crash at my place.
좆됐어, 좆됐다고
We're so fucked.
워싱턴에서 존나게 통수를 치고 다녀서
We've fucked DC over
so many different ways,
이제 아무도 우릴 써주지 않을거야
no one's gonna hire us now.
씨발 보트 때문에 진 빚은
이제 무슨 수로 갚나
How am I gonna pay
for my fucking boat?
아직도 보트 타령이예요 마이크?
Enough about
the fucking boat, Mike.
조명총을 입 안에 쑤셔박고 쏴서
대가리나 터트려버리세요
Take a flare gun, put it in your
mouth, and blow your head off.
말들이 너무 거칠지 않아요?
다들 무슨 괴물같아요
Listen to yourselves.
You people are monsters.
에드, 그 입 좀 다물고 있을래요?
Ed, you really need
to can it right now.
우리 사무실 사람들에
왈가왈부하지 말아요, 알겠어요?
Do not comment
on this office, okay?
수 씨? 저한테 그런 식으로
말하지 마시죠
Hey, Sue, don't talk
to me that way, okay?
수 씨는 부통령님의 비서잖아요
You're the secretary
to the vice president.
가펑클의 로드매니저같은
사람이기도 하고요
That's like being
Garfunkel's roadie, okay?
그래서 여러분이 설리나의 팀원들이군요!
So this is Selina's
team in action.
- 이제야 알 만하네요
- 그러게요
- That explains a lot to me.
- Likewise.
그래도 제 팀원들보단 나아요
Yeah, well, they're actually
better than my team.
제 팀원들은 존나게
좆같은 놈들이라서
My team is just
fucking horrible.
각하?
Ma'am?
안녕
Hi.
무슨 말을 꺼내실 건지 알 것 같은데
괜히 부정탈것같으니 그냥 가만히 있을게요
I think I know what you're gonna
say, but I don't wanna jinx it.
대통령은
POTUS is not
연임을 안 할거래
gonna be running
for a second term.
- 세상에!
- 내가 차기 대선에 나간다!
- Oh, my God!
- I'm gonna run.
Whoa, whoa! Ma'am, give me
the straight poop here.
- 정말로요?
- 그래 진짜로다!
- Is this for real?
- It's totally for real.
감사합니다!*4
Oh, thank you! Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
- 발표해도 되는 건가요?
- 안돼*4!
- Can we make it public?
- No, no, no, no.
- 대통령이 직접 발표하기 전까진 기다려야지
- 알겠습니다!*3
- We got to wait for POTUS to make a statement.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
_
각하, 제가 그동안 연락장교
노릇을 오랫동안 해왔지만
Ma'am, of all the places
that I have liaised,
지금처럼 연락장교 일이
즐거운 적은 없었어요!
I have enjoyed liaising
here the most.
좋아 여러분, 여기서
한없이 좋아하고 있을 때가 아니지
Okay, guys, we don't want to
get ahead of ourselves here.
- 우린 할 일이 많잖아
- 네, 엄청나게 많이 남았죠
- We've got a lot of work.
- Yep, a long road ahead.
- 맞지?
- 저희만 믿고 같이 가시면 됩니다
- Right?
- And we're going all the way.
저는 언제나 부통령님을
믿어왔습니다! 정말이예요
And for the record, ma'am,
I always believed in you.
자네들도 그랬겠지만
나도 내 자신을 믿었고,
Well, I have to say that
I believed in me, too.
- 물론이죠!
- 그래요!
- Of course.
- Yeah.
대통령도 자기 신세가
쫑났다는걸 안 거지
POTUS, he knew the gig was up
도일, 펄롱, 청 모두가
because Doyle, Furlong, Chung
대통령을 등지고
안티로 돌아섰으니까
all turned the party
against him.
대통령은 그냥 고인이나 다름없어
I mean, it was just,
you know, RIP-OTUS.
존나게 침몰하는 타이타닉이지
Just complete sinking shit.
대통령은 알아서 침몰하면 되고
우리는 새로운 역사를 써나가는거죠
No, he had to go. Together we
are going to make history.
백악관으로 향하는겁니다 부통령님
We're going to
the White House, ma'am.
Boom, boom, pow!
Boom, boom, pow.
그래, 맞아!
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Wow.
_
제 똑똑한 두뇌를 부통령님께 바치겠습니다
My brain is at
your service, ma'am.
- 두고 보자고
- 부통령님, 너무 흥분됩니다
- We'll see.
- Ma'am, I am so psyched.
그리고 오늘 과학 전시회에서
연설하신 대본은 청 주지사 발표문 표절이예요
And the science fair speech
was plagiarized from Chung.
Just wanted you
to know that up front.
미리 알려드려야 할 것 같아서요
- 뭐? 뭐라고??
- 네
- What? What? What? What?
- Yep.
- 농담하는거지?
- 아닙니다
- You're kidding.
- No.
- 재앙이 안 일어나면 이상하지
- 인생살이 새옹지마라고
- And so it begins.
- Yeah, with a kick to the tits.
댄, 니가 싸지른 똥은
니가 알아서 처리해
So, Dan, you're gonna have to
clean up your own shitty diaper.
- 알겠지?
- 맡겨만 주십시오
- Got it?
- Not a problem.
당신이랑 나랑은 앞으로
다음 대선 캠페인 전략을 짜야지?
You know what? We got to talk
about the campaign, don't we?
- 불러만 줘, 도와줄게
- 그래, 좋았어
- Okay. I'm right behind you.
- Okay, great.
개리, 데이나한테 전화해
한 90번은 전화했더라
Gary, call Dana.
She's called 90 times.
- 망할!
- 말로 잘 해서 진정시켜
- Shit.
- Talk to her, then sedate her.
부통령 각하, 대통령님께서
나가셨습니다
Ma'am, the president
has left the building.
누가 좆도 신경이나 쓴대?
Who gives a flying fuck?
- 자제하셔야죠 아직
- 미안 미안! 자제가 안되네
- Not yet.
- Sorry. I'm sorry, but I couldn't help it.
각하! 백악관 서관입니다요
Ma'am, West Wing.
- 네 잘못이야
- 아니지!
- This is your fault.
- No, no.
나는 암덩이를 절제해낼 수 없는 단계에
뒤늦게 투입된 거라고!
I didn't arrive soon enough to
be able to cut out the cancer.
아니지! 종양덩이를 잔뜩 달고 온
사람들 데려온게 누군데
Oh, no, I think you arrived with
a man bag filled with tumors.
저것들이야말로 대통령의 문제였어
That was POTUS's problem.
대통령이라는 자가
저런 쓰레기들을 믿고 있었으니
Because he relied
on those two guys.
한 놈은 힘없는 늙다리 루저에
한 놈은 음해 전문 로봇이고 말이야
One a burnt-out loser,
the other a conniving robot.
- 가관입니다
- 최악의 콤보죠
- Crazy.
- Bad combo, yeah.
- 안녕 얘들아!
- 들어오렴!
- Oh, hello, kids.
- Come on in.
세상에! 내내 여기서 기다린거니?
Oh, my God, have you been
here this whole time?
꼬마 과학자들을 위한
M&M 하나씩 나눠주마!
M&Ms for the scientists.
날 따라오지 않겠니?
So come with me
'cause I've got an idea.
내가 직접 백악관 서관을
소개해줄게
I might show you around
the West Wing.
- 우와아아아아!
- 같이 가지 않으련?
- Ahh!
- Would you?
- 너희들도 정부가 좋으니?
- 네
- Do you like government?
- Yes.
- 정치도 좋아하니?
- 네!
- And do you like politics?
- Yeah.
좋구나! 정치라는 것도
결국 사람에 대한 거니까, 안 그래?
Oh, good. Because politics is
about people, don't you think?
- 맞아요
- 생각해보렴,
- Yeah.
- It is when you think about it.
사람이 없으면 정치도 돌아가지 않지
'Cause without people,
you can't have politics.
여기 이 좁은 방 보이니?
See how crowded this is?
무슨 밀실 공포증이라도 걸릴 것 같지 않니?
I mean, it's very
claustrophobic.
내 생각에 대통령님은
자기 직원들만 들여도 방이 꽉 찰거야
I think that the president
should only have her staff here.
대통령 각하든, 여사님이든
아무튼 직원들 말이야
Or his staff.
You know, their staff.
방금 지나간 사람은
난 한 번도 본 적이 없는 사람이란다
I mean, I've never seen--
like that one we just passed,
누군지 모른단다
I don't know
who that person is.
정말 본 적도 없는 사람이야
I've never seen
that person in my life.
여기랑 전혀 상관도 없고 말이야
No business being here.
부통령님은 대니 청 주지사의
연설을 표절한 게 아니예요
Selina did not plagiarize
Danny Chung's speech.
마이크가 이미 설명했을텐데요
Mike's already told you that.
제 말이 마이크를 표절한 거라뇨?
No, I am not plagiarizing Mike.
지루하실 것 잘 아는데,
이봐요, 나도 지루해요
I know it's boring,
but, hey, I'm boring.
이 커튼들은 말이지,
Those curtains there are going.
어머나 흉측하게 생겼네
Wow, those are hideous.
- 우리 계속 사귀는 거 맞지?
- 에드, 나 시간이 없거든?
- We're still together, right?
- Ed, I haven't got time.
우리 둘에게 있어서의 시간 말하는거야?
아니면 일반적 개념의 시간 말하는거야?
Time for us or do you mean
time as a general concept?
안녕하세요 테리,
전화 못 받아서 죄송했습니다
Hi, Terry. I am sorry
I missed your call.
안녕 데이나! 안녕!
들어봐
Hi, Dana. Hey.
Hey, listen.
이 말 꼭 해 주고 싶었어
I just wanted to say that--
알았어, 자기 하고 싶은 말이 있으면
내가 당연히 양보해야지
Okay. Okay. If you've got
something to say, you go first.
당신 어머님이 "오 하느님!"이라고
감탄사 쓰는것도 성경 표절이라 할래요?
Was your mom plagiarizing the Bible
when she said, "Oh, God, oh, God"?
대통령 집무실 중에서 대통령님 의자는
The president's chair
is a couple inches higher
다른 의자보다도
몇인치 더 높게 되어있단다
than the rest of the chairs
in the Oval Office.
그래서 처음 그걸 보고는
"저거 완전 웃겨!"라고 생각했는데,
And I used to think, "Oh, my
God, that's so ridiculous."
지금 생각하면 이해가 된단다
But now I think it makes sense
그런 의자 배치도 좋은
심리학적인 트릭이니까
because I think it's a good
psychological trick.
그런 게 아니라-
아직 말 다 안 끝났다고? 알았어 계속해
Yeah, that's what I-- you're
not finished? Go ahead.
물론 치즈 너무 좋아하시더라고
Oh, she loved the cheese.
정말이야
Loved it.
어른이 되면 저도 부통령님같은
훌륭한 부통령이 되고 싶어요
When I grow up, I want to be
vice president just like you.
그러지 마렴
할 거면 대통령을 해야지
Oh, no, you don't.
You want to be president.
VEEP 시즌2 마지막회입니다
3시즌으로 다시 만나요!
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/